Hello.
Welcome back.
In this lesson, we are going to see how to configure our SDM 32 microcontroller for USP federal complete
communication.
And this actually allows the SDM 32 disco board to be able to communicate with the computer as if it
has a USP to you.
Article that.
So basically, we are going to use the scoreboard to send data to the computer terminal as if we were
doing that over you.
Right.
But this time we're going to be transmitting such data using the USB protocol, rather.
And like I mentioned, this is, um, USP experiment.
The, um, the new clipboard hasn't got a USB port for running these units.
We experiment.
So you want your development board.
Should BDM the disco board at this stage, unless you have one of the new versions of the nuclear board
that allows, um, the US experiment and also, like I mentioned, all of them have the same microcontroller.
If you design your own, you know, your own product, which is to compare it to F for one one, you
can flush the, um, the same code in it and it would work the same way.
You might need to buy, you know, the metallic USP port.
You see the the metal that allows us to connect the US.
But that's the only thing that, you know, the best the only thing the disco house in the nucleus hasn't.
Anyway, I know you get what I'm saying, so I'll stop talking about it.
I'll create a new project to buy a new project.
I'll select my board here.
ASTM three to four.
One, one, and then also like that, the school board here and then double click to open or say no.
Once it is open, Okello or Pinault click over here.
Clippy note.
Say yes.
And then I'm going to come over here.
Often forget what USPS connectivity.
Yeah.
So we come to USP, OTTF is then the mode that we want.
When I said it to device only.
Right.
And we can see a war, you know, D plus and B minus PS activated here.
Next, we need to go to the middle where and make the selection.
I'll come to a middle way over here.
Espey device.
And then what we want is the virtual import communication device class.
Also like this.
OK, next up, so a clock configuration.
Oh, come to system call over here on the RACC.
High speed extend or also like the crystal ceramic resonator and then, um, watch all of this is done.
I'll come over here and because I have this red mark by clock configuration, I'm asked what I want,
the automatic clock issues to be solved.
OK.
Yes.
Over here.
And it's going to sort it out by itself.
It ended up with 72.
I'm going to increase this to nine two six.
You can leave it the same way.
What is important is that you've selected high speed extend all over here to this what we have here.
So this is really straightforward.
There's nothing to change.
We can keep everything as it is your product I.D. and everything.
Yes.
Just what is supposed to be by default.
So we can go ahead and generate our projects or come to project manager over here isolated to change
the competitive Kubi.
The E call this USP on the score virtual comport.
And then I'm going to increase the size a bit.
Oh, I don't know, does euro here?
Of course, it's requires a lot of heat for this project.
OK.
To be honest, if I saw it.
Oh, uh, to be safe.
Oh.
Increase the stock as well.
By included another zero here.
And then once we verify it looks good.
I'll click over here to generate.
A quick over here to open the project, so to transmit data, we need to use the CDC, transmit EFAs
function, and we need to keep the data in a buffer like we saw in the you are two example.
I'm gonna create a buffer to hold the message here.
Also, you integrate on the squatty or call this message and then I'll say size of fifty.
And I'm simply going to see I see yellow from cube IDC.
And then you line over here.
Right.
So this is going to be the message we sent.
So we can go ahead and send it.
Oh, come over here and then I'll use the function CDC on a school cross metaphor's.
And then I passed the, um, the array, it's called message.
And then the size of the array, we can use the screen length function.
And then you take the, um, the arena, which has to be typecast.
To a pointer.
But a string length is found in the string dot h file.
So we need to include that up here.
Right.
Looking good.
Let's put a bit of a delay here, I'll delay or post 400 here.
And then let's build and see what we've got a click away here to build.
OK.
This function is no phone.
So we find this function here.
The function CDC transmits efforts, we find it in the U.S., we divide CDC, I-F.
OK.
This one here, CDC.
If it's defined in here.
Right.
It's defined in this function.
So we simply copy the, um, the head of fall so that we have access to the, um, the functions.
Oh, come over here.
Paste this.
Okay.
Control is too safe.
Click over here to build.
OK.
The warning disappears.
Okay, now let's test it out.
We need to arm.
Click the book to download it.
And then select this.
OK.
And then okay, over here.
Right.
So it's downloaded onto the board.
So actually the debugger by clicking over here.
So this is our USP federal comport demo, so we can occur right here to build of built mine.
And once that is done, we click on the debark and all we need to do is go to the, um, the debugger
and then exit the debugger.
Cause we don't want to debug it.
We just want to flush it onto the board and then see what we can indeed communicate to it.
Our serial program using this method.
So it says build finished, no arrow, no warning to click here to go to debug.
And I'm testing on another computer.
Yeah, I'll click over here, debug.
And it's indicated here four percent, it's trying to launch the virtual comport debug.
OK, so this war we have, so we can just click, we can exit, actually, oh, just exit this because
it's flushed onto the board.
And I've just connected.
Now, you can see my computer has identified that of connected at an estimated 32 virtual compo device
is because, um, running two operating systems on the same computer at us won't be asked.
What I want to connect to Mac or Windows.
Oh, just you wouldn't get this message.
I'll get this message.
Okay.
So once that is done, I'll open Terrytown.
And this is terror term.
Oh, come over here, comport.
You see, we have another comport here.
Federal comport.
And when I click okay, let's see where we get.
I didn't select it comports.
It's still out.
Come one.
So, yeah.
I've just come to zero ports.
Select our virtual imports.
That was number 16 or so.
OK.
And as you can see, hello from Kube, I'd eat just like, um, we wrote over here.
And the reason it's arranged this way is because we forgot to put a slush.
Ah.
But anyway, you can see that we can, um, we can use this as a you art.
So this is our disco board without any external hardware.
We're not using, um, a converter, a USP to FTD converter or any of such converters.
So this is how to um to set up the USP device as a virtual import.
I'll see you in the next lesson.